<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>labs on My Blog : Célestin HERNANDEZ</title>
    <link>/tags/labs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in labs on My Blog : Célestin HERNANDEZ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lab a) : Blog Setup</title>
      <link>/posts/lab-a-setupblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab-a-setupblog/</guid>
      <description>Why Hugo ? I decided to use Hugo because of the challenge it offered. At first, because I was getting behind on the lab, I thought of using a platform that would allow me to instantly and easily create a blog like we see so much nowadays. But I decided not to fall in the Dark Pattern of laziness and got my hands-on Hugo.
How I got started ? At first, I had chosen the Paper Mod which had everything to satisfy me : it was clean, minimalist and readable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab b) : Unity Setup</title>
      <link>/posts/lab-b-unitysetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab-b-unitysetup/</guid>
      <description>Unity ? At the beginning of this course, we had already installed Unity because of our Computer Graphics course. Obviously I had to make sure that my Unity setup was the right one and I also had to add the Android Build Support as suggested by the lab tutorial.
Other than that, I did not have any problems setting up my environment and decided to practice Unity by working on my Computer Graphics&#39; project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab c) : Build your first Unity3D Application</title>
      <link>/posts/lab-c-firstunityapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab-c-firstunityapp/</guid>
      <description>Choosing a project and following its tutorial. For this lab, I decided to follow the Roll a Ball tutorial from Unity. This tutorial alongside the one we got during the lab were enough to get the basics down. And I did not have any problems whatsoever. But I wanted my implementation to be a bit different.
Making my game unique. To give my game a bit of IP Paris spiciness, I added a few things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab d) &amp; e) : Deploying and Implementing a Mobile Application</title>
      <link>/posts/lab-d-e-deployimplementmobileapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab-d-e-deployimplementmobileapp/</guid>
      <description>Deploying Mobile App To deploy my mobile App, I followed the lab tutorial but encountered a problem when I needed to build the app :
 Unable to update the SDK. Please run the SDK Manager manually to make sure you have the latest set of tools and the required platforms installed. See console log for details.
 Well this one was a quick fix, I had to reinstall Unity&amp;rsquo;s tools and it worked but I came across another error while trying to build:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab f) : VR Roll-a-Ball Unity</title>
      <link>/posts/lab-f-rollaballvr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab-f-rollaballvr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
