<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My Blog : Célestin HERNANDEZ</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My Blog : Célestin HERNANDEZ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MRTK : Paris Motor Show</title>
      <link>/posts/parismotorshow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/parismotorshow/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Basically for this project, I tried to get and put to use everything that I had learned throughout the entire course.
The obvious firsts steps were to correctly reconfigure the MRTK profiles and builds settings for the scene, since I had corruption troubles for the app and had to start over and redo the first tutorials for MRTK.
Setting up Before getting too much into technicalities, it&amp;rsquo;s important to setup our scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human 3D Pose Reconstruction : Computer Vision Lab</title>
      <link>/posts/computervisionlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/computervisionlab/</guid>
      <description>Task 1 : Read the 2DTXT file and draw the keypoints on original video. To complete that task, we must understand how keypoints shall be drawn on the video. Basically we need to map what&amp;rsquo;s inside the OP2DTXT folder into the corresponding video.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27  all_coordinates = np.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recurrent Neural Networks</title>
      <link>/posts/reccurentneuralnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reccurentneuralnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Introduction During this course, I had the pleasure of discovering what Recurrent Neural Networks were. Since the evaluation associated to this course is mostly based on my understanding on the course, I&amp;rsquo;ll try and be the clearest possible to show how much I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
Sequence Modelling As said in the course, sequential data is everywhere. Wether in stock exchange data, music, texts, proteines, audio etc. What we mean by sequence is an enumeration of possibly repeated objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning : Theory and the CartPole game</title>
      <link>/posts/reinforcement-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reinforcement-learning/</guid>
      <description>What is Reinforcement Learning ? Introduction This will basically serve as a toolbox / summary of what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about Reinforcement Learning either throughout the course or with my own exploration.
I was extremely excited witht the idea of learning more about Reinforcement Learning : ever since I discovered the potential of Artficial Intelligence and Machine Learning, I was blown away by how people were actually programming AI to play games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab a) : Blog Setup</title>
      <link>/posts/lab-a-setupblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab-a-setupblog/</guid>
      <description>Why Hugo ? I decided to use Hugo because of the challenge it offered. At first, because I was getting behind on the lab, I thought of using a platform that would allow me to instantly and easily create a blog like we see so much nowadays. But I decided not to fall in the Dark Pattern of laziness and got my hands-on Hugo.
How I got started ? At first, I had chosen the Paper Mod which had everything to satisfy me : it was clean, minimalist and readable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab b) : Unity Setup // Computer Graphics&#39; 3D platformer</title>
      <link>/posts/lab-b-unitysetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab-b-unitysetup/</guid>
      <description>Unity ? At the beginning of this course, we had already installed Unity because of our Computer Graphics course. Obviously I had to make sure that my Unity setup was the right one and I also had to add the Android Build Support as suggested by the lab tutorial.
Other than that, I did not have any problems setting up my environment and decided to practice Unity by working on my Computer Graphics&#39; project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab c) : Build your first Unity3D Application</title>
      <link>/posts/lab-c-firstunityapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab-c-firstunityapp/</guid>
      <description>Choosing a project and following its tutorial. For this lab, I decided to follow the Roll a Ball tutorial from Unity. This tutorial alongside the one we got during the lab were enough to get the basics down. And I did not have any problems whatsoever. But I wanted my implementation to be a bit different.
Making my game unique. To give my game a bit of IP Paris spiciness, I added a few things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab d) &amp; e) : Deploying and Implementing a Mobile Application</title>
      <link>/posts/lab-d-e-deployimplementmobileapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab-d-e-deployimplementmobileapp/</guid>
      <description>Deploying Mobile App To deploy my mobile App, I followed the lab tutorial but encountered a problem when I needed to build the app :
 Unable to update the SDK. Please run the SDK Manager manually to make sure you have the latest set of tools and the required platforms installed. See console log for details.
 Well this one was a quick fix, I had to reinstall Unity&amp;rsquo;s tools and it worked but I came across another error while trying to build:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab f) : VR Roll-a-Ball Unity and course&#39;s feedback</title>
      <link>/posts/lab-f-rollaballvr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lab-f-rollaballvr/</guid>
      <description>A VR Implementation that became a failure. Well, this is not the happiest I&amp;rsquo;ve been. I had kept the VR Lab as far away as I could from me but maybe I should have put more thought in it because it ended up as a complete failure but I still want to write a blogpost for it.
I had basically started the lab on Evry Campus on an Occulus Rift but switched to a Quest right after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 01 : Affordances</title>
      <link>/posts/lecture1-affordances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lecture1-affordances/</guid>
      <description>Finding a good and a bad affordance. When we talked about affordances in our course, the main example that I kept in mind was the one about door handles. I had never truly thought about their design, but once we talked about it, I was able to vividly remeber the many times in which I pushed instead of pulled and wondered who was the designer of such an atrocity.
That&amp;rsquo;s why my first example of a daily affordance is this door handle:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 02 : Gestalt Laws</title>
      <link>/posts/lecture2-gestaltlaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lecture2-gestaltlaws/</guid>
      <description>Gestalt laws, an old passion of mine. When we talked about Gestalt laws during our lecture, I immediatly thought about the dontdeadopeninside and CrappyDesign subreddits. If you&amp;rsquo;ve never checked them out, I can only recommend you to do so. They basically concatenates the very best of the worst of design, and were basically used as the a precious database for this lecture. What was truly insightful for me during this lecture was the fact that I had always laughed about problems like these without ever even knowing that they were related to Gestalt Laws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 03 : Dark Patterns</title>
      <link>/posts/lecture3-darkpatterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lecture3-darkpatterns/</guid>
      <description>Finding and documenting two Dark Design Patterns. This lecture has hag a great echo on me, and has helped me realise how sneaky and insidious Dark Design Patterns truly are.
As for the first example I decided to document, I decided to give you a bit of context on how I came across this Dark Pattern. I recently had to change my laptop and I chose this one :   My new setup just for attention, please notice that I&amp;#39;m using it to work   I chose a french market place to buy it and since it was pretty expensive, I wanted to save as much money as I could.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 04 : Presenting one HCI Researcher</title>
      <link>/posts/lecture4-presentinghciresearcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lecture4-presentinghciresearcher/</guid>
      <description>Finding an HCI Reasearcher To find the perfect candidate for this lecture, I decided to use a classical technique. I went on Google Scholar, typed in Human Computer Interaction and checked the authors of the most quoted papers.
That&amp;rsquo;s how I came across Gregory D. Abowd, because he is one of the coauthors of the second edition of the HCI&amp;rsquo;s Bible : &amp;ldquo;Human-computer interaction&amp;rdquo;.
  The man himself   Presenting Gregory D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 05 : The Ultimate Display by Ivan Sutherland</title>
      <link>/posts/lecture5-ultimatedisplayivansutherland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lecture5-ultimatedisplayivansutherland/</guid>
      <description>What has Ivan Sutherland successfully predicted ? In his 1965 article The Ultimate Display, Ivan Sutherland wonders what the future will look like for computers, displays and the human interactions that will take place between them. To sum up efficiently which of his predictions were true, I will directly quote him and try to explain what he was describing that is actually existing today.
  &amp;ldquo;It is likely that new display equipment will have area-filling capability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 06 : Input Devices and Interaction Paradigms</title>
      <link>/posts/lecture6-inputdevicesinteractionparadigms-copie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lecture6-inputdevicesinteractionparadigms-copie/</guid>
      <description>Presenting and classifying a new/failed input device/technique While browsing the internet to find a new type of input device I came across what i first thought to be an atrocity.   Meet the OrbiTouch, the keyless mouse and keyboard   As the description suggests, the OrbiTouch acts as a keyboard and mouse. You could argue that it might me a gesture driven interface but I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it as a GUI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 07, 08 &amp; 09 : Ideate, Sketch, Use and Evaluate</title>
      <link>/posts/lecture7-8-9-ideateprototypeusage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lecture7-8-9-ideateprototypeusage/</guid>
      <description>Ideating at least three potential human abilities enhancing apps in AR. Okay so right out of the gate when I heard enhacing human abilities I immediatly thought about sports because this is where our most basic abilities as animals are displayed. I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge sports person and that&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;m not that good at coaching myself. I either lack motivation or advices to successfully complete programs / exercises. That&amp;rsquo;s why I would to introduce you to A(R)pollon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 10 : The shape of smartphones</title>
      <link>/posts/lecture10-theshapeofsmartphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lecture10-theshapeofsmartphones/</guid>
      <description>Discussing the evolution of shape of smartphones. Why did they change their shape ?   Simplified evolution   This picture may be considered off topic or too caricatural, but I believe it displays perfectly the evolutions the smartphone&amp;rsquo;s (and cellphone&amp;rsquo;s) shape has faced throughout the years.
The first phone of its kind was a big technological leap, so its design was not truly its best asset. Of course it did fit the shape of the hand but it looked so bulky and hard to maneuver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 11 : Computer of the 21st Century</title>
      <link>/posts/lecture11-computer21stcentury/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lecture11-computer21stcentury/</guid>
      <description>Are we already living in a world of ubiquitous computing ? If we follow Mark Wesiser&amp;rsquo;s point of view that I&amp;rsquo;ll describe below, we are not yet in a world of ubiquitous computing but I do believe that we are getting pretty close to it. The IoT and the always expanding capabilities of our devices has brought us closer to such a world. I believe that we have all the pieces (nearly) to build such a world but this is not our priority right now and I guess our generation is not ready for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 12 : Most Downloaded Application in the future MR App Store </title>
      <link>/posts/lecture12-mrappstore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lecture12-mrappstore/</guid>
      <description>Sketching and presenting three application that will be among the most downloaded in the future MR AppStore. Okay so I&amp;rsquo;m definetly not the best Paint3D user and the quality may not be top notch, but I do believe that drawings are the best way to convey ideas. I&amp;rsquo;ll present 3 basic app ideas that may not be revolutionnary but will sure be succesful if they end up actually existing.
Your browser does not support the video tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My very first post on this blog</title>
      <link>/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>It has been a long way from the very first course of HCI to the publishing of this article, but we are here. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain more in depth the choices I made and the reasoning behind it in my next post about our Hugo Lab. See you there ! 👋
  Happy of my success    &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s one small step for man, one giant leap for mankind.&amp;rdquo; Or something along those lines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
